(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-29T18:46:06.399530",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
あれ？
Huh?
ママと一緒に影ナリするって聞いたのに、
I heard I was going to do shadow narration with Mama, but...
ここどこや？
where is this?
しかも、ママどこ？
And besides, where's Mama?
ママ！
Mama!
ママどこいったん？
Mama, where'd you go?
ママ！
Mama!
ママどこいったーん！？
Mama, where'd you gooo?!
うーん、どうも帰れえんからな。
Hmm, I guess I can't go home, huh.
まあ、ほんならえしし一人でも始めたか。
Well, in that case, I might as well start by myself.
ピンポンパンポン♪
Ding-dong, ding-dong.
本日は美水しな追生放送にお越しいただき、誠にありがとうございます。
Thank you very much for attending Mizushina's live broadcast today.
開演に先立ちまして、ご来場のお客さまにお願い申し上げます。
Before the show starts, we kindly ask our attending guests for the following.
なんであんねん！なんであんねん！
Why's that! Why's that!
なんか声聞こえる！どこどこどこ？
I hear a voice! Where, where, where?
どこやねん！どこにおるねん！
Where the heck are you! Where are you!
下見ろ！下！
Look down! Down!
下？下？
Down? Down?
ここ！
Here!
ちっちゃ！ちっちゃ！
So tiny! So tiny!
どうないしたん？ここ！
What happened? Here!
あんた、あんた！
You, you!
ママ？ママだよ！
Mama? It's Mama!
え、ほんまに！
Huh, seriously?!
こんな、こんなちっちゃくなっちゃったよ！
I became so, so tiny!
ええやん！
That's cute!
よしよしよしよし！
Good girl, good girl!
かわいいな！お前どうしたん？
How cute! What happened to you?
変なクスリ飲まされた？
Were you given some weird medicine?
そうなの、そうなの！
That's right, that's right!
名探偵やな！
You're a master detective!
どうしたん、あんた？
What's wrong with you?
もっとやって、もっとやって！
Do it more, do it more!
はい、ここジフに使ってください。
Here, please use this as a GIF.
もっとやって、もっとやって！
Do it more, do it more!
かわいいやん、そんなんちっちゃくなって！
How cute, getting all tiny like that!
水瀬に会いたかったよ！
Mizuse wanted to meet you!
一緒にいたかったよ！
I wanted to be together!
そんな、そんなちっちゃい姿で言われてもな。
Even if you say that in such a tiny form...
はい、あずき影ナレをやります！
Alright, Azuki's shadow narration starts now!
あ、水瀬に今日乗られちゃうとこだったんだけど、
Ah, I was almost stolen by Mizuse today, but...
え、本日はあずき生放送にお越しいただき、誠にありがとうございます。
Uh, thank you very much for coming to Azuki's live broadcast today.
お待たせしまして、
Now then,
ご来場のお客さまにお願いを申し上げます。
I have a request for everyone present here.
まぁーす。
♪
え、ただいまよりコイントスが始まります。
A coin toss is about to begin right now!
ぜひ、みなさま、
♪
コメントやSNSで一緒に盛り上がってください。
Please get hyped together with us in the comments and on social media!
ねーい！
♪
はい！ハッシュタグは「AZKi生放送」です。
The hashtag is #AzkiNamahousou!
たくさん感想も投稿してくれると嬉しいです。
We'd be super happy if you'd post a lot!
お願いします！
♪
ちびAZKiも一緒に応援します！
Chibi Azki, let's cheer together too!
あ、あっ！
♪
あ、あんた出れるんじゃないの？
Wait, can you even do that?
ちびAZKi、応援します！
Chibi Azki, cheer them on!
ちびAZKi応援します！よくできましたー！
Chibi Azki, cheer them on! Look, you did great!
よくできたでしょうー！
♪
じゃあね、みんなちょっと待っててね！
Alright everyone, just wait a second!
はーい！
♪
猫になって甘えたい
I want to become a cat and be spoiled.
猫になって愛されたいよ
I want to become a cat and be loved.
猫になってお昼寝させて
I want to become a cat and take a nap.
起きたら100万登録いってないかな？
I wonder if I've hit a million followers by the time I wake up?
猫ならばいける！
If you're a cat, you can do anything!
いぇい！いぇい！みんなで一緒に盛り上がっていきましょう！
Yeah, let's get hyped! Let's get excited!
許したけどちゃんとね、毎月ツイートしなくちゃ。
Wait, but make sure to properly like and retweet every year.
台書きなんてなんでそんなに引っ張って！
Why did you even write a script?
完璧な140カラット そうさ透き通ってテリと 心が折れる日常を追い！
Staring into eyes that are a pure 140-carat sapphire, my heart breaks—let's chase after it!
皆みなっしぇ歌ってて！
Everyone, please sing along!
みんなで一緒なら大丈夫！おーう！
We can totally do this, right? Everyone, it's alright! Woah!
だから応援よろしくね！宝石に甘やかして 毎しなかい全面見てね！
So please give me lots of support! Spoil me with your absolute love, and watch my every single move!
でも今日はやっぱり
Even so, today is...
本当にね、長い！
Really been a long time!
こんな私もちゃんと見てほしい
I want you to look at someone like me properly too.
無条件の愛が欲しい
I want more of your unconditional love.
だから猫になって甘えたいよ！
So I want to become a cat and be spoiled!
猫になって愛されたいよ！
I want to become a cat and be loved!
猫になってお昼寝させて！
I want to become a cat and take a nap!
起きたら100万登録だ！
I wonder if I've hit a million followers by the time I wake up!
猫になって輝きたいの！
I want to shine by becoming a cat!
猫になって買い得くするよ！
I'll make you fall head over heels by becoming a cat!
もっと君に伝わりますように
I'm sure it will reach you someday!
猫ならばいける！みんなにゃおにゃおしていってね！
If you're a cat, you can do anything! Everyone, let's meow together!
お散歩してたら公園で可愛いワンちゃん見つけたよ！
I took a walk in the park and found a cute puppy!
なんでよっとしたら吠えられた！やっぱ猫になりたい
When I tried to pet it, it barked at me. I guess I really want to be a cat.
でもどうすればいい？
But what should I do to become a cat?
猫のなり方 隠れてないでほんとしてほしい
I want you to make me one without hiding it.
作って作ってほしい
Please make one for me!
だから猫になって抱きしめられたい！
So I want to become a cat and be hugged tightly!
猫になってなでなでしてよ！
I want to become a cat and be petted!
猫になって餌を与えて！
I want to become a cat and be given food!
山モリチュールをよろしくね！
Please treat the mountain-climbing chinchilla well!
猫になって恋してたいの！
I want to become a cat and be pampered!
猫になって笑い合おうよ！
I want to become a cat and laugh together!
もっとみんな猫になろうよ！
Let's all become cats soon!
みんな、最後まで盛り上がっていってねー！
Everyone, let's get hyped right to the very end!
本当やっぱり
Really though...
起きたら5月22日
Today is May 22nd.
ライン目茶苦茶出てる、でもまあしゃあない！
My line is super weird, but oh well, it can't be helped!
逆に緑にしましょう！
Let's make it green instead!
だから！だから猫になって甘えたい！
So... So I want to become a cat and be spoiled!
猫になって愛されたい！
I want to become a cat and be loved!
猫になって
Be a cat,
お昼寝させて
let me take a nap,
起きたら 百万登録だ
and when I wake up, hit a million subscribers!
猫になって 輝きたいの
I want to become a cat and shine,
猫になって 飼い馴らすよ
I want to become a cat and tame you!
もっと君に伝わりますように
Hoping it reaches you even more.
もっと もっと 猫になって 甘やかされたい ずっと
More, more, I want to be a cat and be pampered forever.
猫になって 抱きしめられたい もっと
I want to be a cat and be hugged even more.
猫になって 恋してたいの
I want to be a cat and be in love,
猫になって 笑い合おうよ
let's laugh together as cats.
もっとみんな 猫になろうよ
Let's all become cats even more.
猫ならば いける
If we're cats, we can do it.
君となら いけるー！
With you, we can do anything!
にゃーにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow!
ほんもの の 猫だ！
A real cat!
猫やー！
A cat!
にゃーにゃーにゃーにゃーにゃー
Meow, meow, meow, meow, meow!
最後はみんなで
Finally, everyone together,
せーの！ にゃー！
Ready, set, meow!
ということで、改めてまして、AZKi！
And with that, once again, I'm AZKi!
え、今日はAZKi生放送にお越しいただき、ありがとうございます！
Thank you so much for coming to AZKi's live broadcast today!
はい、今日はね、スペシャルなゲストをお呼びしております！
Yes, today we have invited a very special guest!
水科葵！
Aoi Mizushina!
わあ！みんなこんばんは水科！
Yay! Good evening, everyone, it's Mizushina!
こんばんは水科！こんばんは水科！
Good evening, Mizushina! Good evening, Mizushina!
ママどんな立ち位置してんの？キラキラキラキラ…
Mama, what kind of pose are you doing? Sparkle sparkle...
奈良満開の大阪と、あんこ大好き、音楽大好き耳おの、水科いこうと、水科な青いや。よろしくお願いしまーす！
From full-bloom Nara to Osaka, love red bean paste, love music... nice to meet you!
よろしく！ママ呼んでくれてありがとう！
Nice to meet you! Thank you for inviting me, Mama!
久しぶりだよ！会いたかったよ！会いたかったよ！会いたかったよ！
It's been so long! I wanted to see you! I wanted to see you! I wanted to see you!
もうね、水科とはね、本当にね、2年前、2年前の、え、AZKiのAZラジオMAXで一緒に共演してしてからもうずっとね、色々ラジオも、3人目のラジオとかも一緒に文化放送でやらせてもらったりとかして…
You know, Mizushina and I co-starred 2 years ago on AZKi's "AZ Radio MAX," and ever since, we've done radio shows together...
そう、長く、長く、末永く、これからも本当に…そうなんですよ。嬉しいよ。
Yes, for a long, long time, and forever going on... Exactly. I'm so happy.
そういうことでもうちょっと、まあ、会えない、水科に会えないこの気持ちをこうどうにかして…
Because of that, I wanted to somehow express this feeling of not being able to see Mizushina...
どうにかして、そう、ちょっと遠距離？遠距離、そう、遠距離恋愛？なるほどね。
Somehow, yeah, long distance? Long distance romance? I see.
もうちょっと、はもうこれはライブに要望と。ちょっともうね、
And so, this is a request for the live show. And now,
いやいや、もう警察に呼んで、そう、警察にちょっと今回お呼びしたんですけども、2つ返事でね。
No, no, we called the police—well, we invited her this time—and she answered right away.
めちゃめちゃ嬉しかった！
I was so happy!
すぐ出ますって、もうね、本当すぐ、私出ますと。すぐ返事をしてくれて、今日はね、来てくれました。イエーイ！
“I’ll be right out,” she said immediately. She replied right away and came here today! Yay!
いや、今日はね、もう水科のお友達を楽しんでもらって、最後までみんなと一緒に盛り上がって行きたいと思います！
Yeah, today I hope you all enjoy Mizushina's company and get hyped up with everyone until the end!
はーい！はーい！はい、ということでね、水科が来てくれたんで、たっぷりね、歌を歌っていきたいと思います。
Yay! Yay! So since Mizushina came over, we're going to sing plenty of songs.
はい。続いては、あの、あの曲です。お！
Yes. Next up is... that song. Oh!
初めてね、AZKiと水科が一緒に歌った、あの曲を歌いきたいと思います。思い出だ。思い出だ。それでは、聞いてください。鮮紅の花。
The song that AZKi and Mizushina sang together for the very first time. We want to sing that song. It's memories. So, please listen. "Senkou no Hana".
箱庭に閉じ込められた
Trapped inside a miniature garden,
小さく震える少年少女は
the trembling boy and girl
痛みから逃げたくて
wanted to escape from the pain,
彷徨いながら 信じて進んでく
wandering while believing as they moved forward.
無慈悲で暗い 過去の記憶
Memories of a merciless, dark past
白い目が 行く道を閉ざす
and cold stares block the path ahead.
心の花は 枯らすまいと
Hoping not to let the flower of the heart wither away,
灰色の空 響く銃声
a gunshot echoes across the gray sky.
鮮紅の花 舞い上がるように
Like a scarlet flower dancing into the air,
真実さえも 偽りと化す
even truth turns into falsehood.
偽りと化す
turning truth into falsehood.
その悪夢から
From that nightmare,
目を覚ますため
to awaken,
覚悟を胸に 君のための
with resolve in my chest, to be your
盾となる
shield.
戦場に繋がれた
Bound to the battlefield,
何も知らない少年少女は
innocent boys and girls...
操り人形のように
like marionettes,
物語通り争いに飲まれる
swallowed up by the staged conflict.
理性が果て惑うがままに
As reason fades and doubt takes over,
命の火燃やし続けてく
they keep burning the fire of life.
世界の声に耳を塞ぎ
Shutting their ears to the world's voice,
灰の空響く蛮声
savage cries echo through the ash-gray sky.
鮮紅の花舞い散るように
Like scarlet flowers fluttering down,
破壊の心強さに変えて
turn the heart's destruction into strength.
このあがきが罪ではないと
Whispering from the depths of groans
呻きの底で君の声が震えてる
that this struggle is not a sin, your voice trembles.
ニセモノなんて必要ない
Fakes are unnecessary;
ホンモノの言葉だけでいい
genuine words are all we need.
慈しみ手と手取り合って
Joining hands with tenderness,
運命を切り開いてく
we carve open our destiny.
鮮紅の花舞い上がるように
Like scarlet flowers soaring high,
真実さえも偽りと化す
turning even truth into falsehood.
その悪夢から目を覚ますため
To awaken from that nightmare,
決意を胸に君のための
with resolve in my chest, to be your
盾となる
shield.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
水希ちゃっかっこいい！
Mizuki, so cool!
ママもかっこいい！
Mama is cool too!
あのね、リハーサルのときにね、あの水希ちゃんはね、セリフを言わなかったのよ。
You know, during rehearsal, Mizuki didn't say her lines.
ちょっと、ちょっと
Wait, wait!
なんで行くせんの！
Why are you exposing me?!
違うだから
No, that's because—
いや本番に強い女だから
I'm a woman who shines on stage!
だってリハ恥ずかしくて声出ないんだもん。
Rehearsals are just too embarrassing to speak up!
リハで先を越せ先を越せって
And you kept telling me in rehearsals to go ahead!
いやめっちゃかっこよかったよ。
Well, it was super cool.
ちょっとね、ゾワゾワゾワって、みんなもゾワゾワゾワってしたよね。
It gave me goosebumps, and everyone got goosebumps too, right?
いやなんか楽しくなっちゃって、やっちゃったよね。
Well, I just got so into the fun of it.
いや、いい、いいですね。
Yeah, that's great, isn't it?
まあ、えっとママもね、今回ねまた初めてコラボしてきて、で、バンバンスクレタと
Well, Mama and I collaborated for the first time this time, and with Bang Bang Sukreta...
そう、そのバンバンを一緒に、そう、水希先生に教えてもらってまして
That's right, we did that Bang Bang together, taught by Teacher Mizuki.
完璧！やったー！
Perfect! Yay!
さすが！
As expected!
いや、超超かっこよかった！
Man, it was super, super cool!
はい、ということで、ここからはですね、ソロパートやっていきたいと思います！
Right, so from here on, we'd like to do solo parts!
ということで、皆さん、水希のカレーな歌声聴いてってください。
So everyone, please listen to Mizuki's splendid singing voice.
あまりまい
(Laughs)
それじゃあまずは水希から、頑張ってね！
Well then, first up is Mizuki, do your best!
ありがとう、がんばるよ。
Thanks, I'll do my best.
ああ、一人になっちまったね。
Ah, I've ended up all alone.
じゃあ、一回、あの、今からめちゃめちゃ、あの、なんだろう、
Well then, once, um, from now on, super, um, I wonder...
少し運動するので先水分補給させてください。
Since I'll be moving around a bit, let me grab some water first.
ふう、これで大丈夫だわ。
Phew, I'm good now.
美味しいお水でしたということで、
That was some delicious water! So,
次の曲がですね、
as for the next song...
もうね、とにかく大変です。なんやろ、一人で歌うのも大変やし、踊るのも大変やしっていう曲なんやけど、
Man, it's just so tough! It's a song where singing alone is tough, and dancing is tough, but
すごいAZKiにとって、この楽曲は道しるべにもなってて、すごく大切な曲になってます。
for AZKi, this track has become a guiding light and a very precious song.
それでは、この曲から聞いてください。
Well then, please listen to this song.
彩面境界のモノローグ
[Title: Monologue of the Painted Boundary]
めくるめく 意識のサーバー 遥か
Far beyond the dizzying server of consciousness,
錆び付いた 時が Let's go
rusted time—Let's go!
染み込んで 日常を描けば
Soaking in, if I sketch our daily life,
映し出す しっかりと鍵のかかった
it projects shadows locked up tight—
Dive! 願いの果てまで 飛び込んでゆけ
Dive! Leap all the way to the end of our wishes,
迷妄も消し去り 理解を込める
erasing delusions and putting in understanding.
夜闇に隠されたことを ひたすら剥き出す想いを
All the things hidden in the night, feelings purely laid bare,
体中駆け巡る
racing throughout my body.
全てを信じたら 願いは手のなかに
If I believe in everything, my wish is in my hands.
I wanna fly! 私たちは夢を渡り
I wanna fly! We cross over dreams,
遥か備えた 辿り着くためさえ
prepared far ahead, even just to reach there,
現実を邪魔されても 構わない
even if reality tries to obstruct us, I don't care.
暗い世界の海の底に消えて
Vanishing into the bottom of the dark world's sea,
道を閉ざされたとしても
even if our path is closed off,
切り開けた波は Go away!
the waves we carved open—Go away!
深い世界の海に消えて
Vanishing into the sea of the deep world,
道を閉ざされたとしても
even if our path is closed off,
切り開けた波は Go away!
the waves we forged ahead—Go away!
夢の淵に姿見せたリア(ル)
The reality that showed its figure at the edge of a dream—
見えたのは虚構かそれが光か
was what I saw fiction, or was it light?
虚空の果てには 現実の僕が 今も眠る
At the edge of the void, the real me is still sleeping.
Dive! 世界はひとたび
Dive! Every time the world
またたきを止めて
stops its twinkling,
無数の闇が 時を動かす
countless darknesses set time in motion.
ここでもない この宇宙に迷い込み
Straying into this universe that is nowhere else,
生きている その意味を知るわけを
knowing the meaning and reason why I'm living—
退屈に 刻まれた 日常を
etching the boring everyday life into time,
ひたすら 剥き出す 想いを 体中
and letting feelings purely laid bare course through my body.
駆け巡る 全てを信じたら
If I believe in everything,
願いは手の中に
my wish is in my hands.
I wanna fly! これまでの生き様は
I wanna fly! The way I've lived up until now
見せずとも これからの生き様を
doesn't need to be shown; the way I'll live from now on
現実と幻想は 重ねて描き出す
will intertwine reality and illusion to paint our story.
シナリオが 摘み上げられた 畳も
Even if the scenario picks up and folds up the tatami mat,
変えてゆこう I wanna fly!
let's change it—I wanna fly!
僕らは 息をひそめ
We hold our breath,
退屈な 今を 暴してる
exposing this boring present.
たとえ 現実に 邪魔されても
Even if reality tries to get in the way,
揺るがない 星はしない
it won't waver; it won't die out.
世界の 隅に すべての 心を寄せた
Gathering all my heart into the corners of the world,
としても この願いだけ とわに
even so, this wish alone will eternally
放たれ
be released!
巡り巡る 今とまぼろし
Spinning and turning, the present and illusion,
流れ狂う 底の深さに
flowing wildly into the depths of the bottom—
見えたのは 鏡か それが 光か
was what I saw a mirror, or was it light?
ゆらり ゆらり 漂いながら
Drifting, swaying gently,
変わらない 毎日 繰り返してる
repeating the same unchanging days,
ひとりぼっちの なれっこだから
since I'm so used to being all alone,
滲んだ声 海にそっと伏せた
I softly hid my blurred voice in the sea.
遠く霞みゆく 視線の先に
Far away, beyond my hazy gaze,
何が待ってるの？
what is waiting for me?
どんな表情で どんな色を
With what expression, in what color...
してるかな 気づいて
...am I wearing? I've realized
しまったよ この気持ち
this feeling.
もっと止められない
I can't stop it anymore.
銀色世界 広がっていく
A silvery world is spreading out,
触れたことのない 温もりを感じてる
feeling a warmth I've never touched before.
響き渡れ 歌声 あなたのもとに
Resound far and wide, my singing voice, reaching you.
夢が紡ぐおとぎ話 1ページめくり
Turning a page of the fairytale spun by dreams,
始まる “メロウ”
beginning "mellow."
光り ゆらり 流れながら
Glowing, drifting and swaying,
踊る姿に 見とれている
I'm captivated by the dancing figure.
ひとりぼっちの 辛さを捨てて
Leaving behind the pain of being alone,
希望の先へ 飛び込んでゆこう
let's leap forward into hope.
降りるはずのない 雨に打たれて
Beaten down by rain that shouldn't be falling,
溺れてしまいそうになって も
even if I feel like I'm drowning,
魔法の言葉を 思い出してと唱えたら
when I recall magic words and chant them,
未来へあふれだす この気持ち
this feeling overflows toward the future.
もっと止められない
I can't stop it anymore.
銀色世界 果てしなく続く
A silvery world continuing endlessly,
この場所から 限りなく愛を伝えるよ
from this place, I will convey boundless love.
泡となって 溶けてしまうその前に
Before it turns into bubbles and melts away,
夢が紡ぐおとぎ話
a fairytale spun by dreams,
1ページめくり 刻む “メロウ”
turning a page, engraving "mellow".
響き渡れ ときめき あなたのもとに
Resound far and wide, my excitement, reaching you.
夢が紡ぐおとぎ話
A fairytale spun by dreams,
1ページめくる 明日への “メロウ”
turning a page, "mellow" toward tomorrow.
当然のこと 誰も 疑わないの
No one ever doubts the obvious thing.
息をしている ように見えている
It looks like I'm just breathing.
背の裏側 私にとってのなにか
On the flip side, something precious to me...
孤独が 独々している
Solitude is pulsing away.
戦っても 腐らずに
Even if I fight, without rotting away,
ここで 歌うよ ボタン一つの 命
I'll sing right here, a life on a single button.
最後まで 私のこと 覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
消えてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよね
I feel like I'm going to fade away, understand me, please understand.
本当のことなの? 恋と惜しさは違うでしょ
Is it really true? Love and regret are different, right?
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
If you forget about me, I will disappear.
命のような 夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
息をしている だから生きている
I'm breathing, therefore I'm alive.
自己証明を 欲しがって 欲しがっているんだ
Craving, desperately craving proof of my existence.
鼓動が止まって
My heartbeat stops,
動かなくなって
and stops moving.
そんな私を 君は笑ってくれるかな
Will you smile at someone like me?
孤独が 独々している
Solitude is pulsing away,
嫌われても 腐らずに ここで歌うよ
even if I'm disliked, without rotting, I'll sing right here.
気分次第で
Depending on my mood,
命
my life...
最後まで私の こと見届けてくれるの
Will you make my voice echo until the very end?
凍えてしまいそうなの わかってよ わかってよね
I feel like I'm going to freeze, understand me, please understand.
声が聞こえるんだよ 塩辛い涙が出ちゃうぞ
I can hear a voice, salty tears are about to fall.
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
If you forget about me, I will disappear.
命のような 夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
染み込んだ あの日を
That day soaked deep within...
軽くいじらないで やめて
Don't mess with it lightly, stop it.
それが生きる糧に なるのかな
Will that become nourishment to keep on living?
大丈夫 ずっと私は 歌い続けるから
It's okay, I'll keep on singing forever.
最後まで私は 生きているか分からないけど
Until the very end, I don't know if I'm truly alive, but...
君がくれた言葉は 確かに残ってる
the words you gave me definitely remain.
最後まで私の こと覚えててくれるの
Will you remember me until the very end?
死んでしまうだろう わかんない わかんないよね
I'll probably shatter inside, I don't know, you don't know either.
痛いぐらい 気持ちが シンクロする時もあるけど
Sometimes our feelings synchronize painfully, but...
君が忘れちゃったら 私は いなくなるの
if you forget about me, I will disappear.
命のような 夢を見てるよ
I'm dreaming a dream that feels like life itself.
またね バイバイ
See you later, bye-bye.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
水無瀬のソロパートが良すぎた
The piano solo part was way too good!
もうね、おばあちゃん疲れた
Oh man, this grandma is tired!
おばあちゃん 息切れてる おばあちゃんマジで！
Grandma is out of breath. Seriously, Grandma!
おばあちゃん久しぶりに水飲もう？おばあちゃんちょっと一口飲むからね！
Grandma, let's drink some water for the first time in a while. I'll take a sip, Grandma!
そうね。ふふっ。
That's right. Hehe.
いやでもすごかったもう 軽音王国モノローグからメロローグにかけてのもう
Yeah, but it was amazing, from the light music club's medley all the way to the ballad...
これ歌いきるんかと という
"Can I really sing all of this?"
さすがにね、おばあちゃんもね、動きながらはね
Even grandma, moving around while doing it—
きつい、きつい、きつい
it's so tough, so tough, so tough!
あの、人様のチャンネルでこう、あの、きつい、きつい、きつい、やり切るっていうね
Doing this on someone else's channel... it's so tough, but seeing it through to the end!
いやでもね、でそのあとの命また一緒に歌えたから
But you know, being able to sing "Inochi" together afterwards—
いや、そう、だからその、メローの流れからの命、めっちゃよかったよね
Yeah, right! The transition from the mellow part into "Inochi" was so good!
うん、でも爆エモ！爆エモ！爆エモ待ち
Yeah! Total emotional overload! Total emotional overload! Waiting for that emotional peak!
爆アゲとか爆エモとかライブ？そう、あのリハ終わったから、そっ、爆アゲ
Like "Bakuage" or "Bakuemo" live? Yeah, once rehearsal finished, "Bakuage"!
いやそう、水詩シーにね、命はそうカバーしてもらったりとか
Yeah, Mizushi-chan even covered "Inochi" for me, and—
それこそね、あのショットガンローズのライブとかでもね、歌ってもらったりとかして、めちゃくちゃそう思い出のある曲なので
And even at the "Shotgun Rose" live, you sang it for me... it's a song full of memories, so—
今日もまたこうやってなんだろう、こうやってまた歌えることの喜び
I'm just so happy to be able to sing it together again like this today.
ねー！
Right!
まさかまた一緒に歌えると思ってなかったから、めっっちゃ嬉しい！
I never thought we'd get to sing together again, so I'm super, super happy!
そう、なんかもうただただライブを楽しんでいる
Yeah, it's like we're just purely enjoying the live performance.
なあ、オタクか？
Are you an otaku?
オタク、なんかちょっとそれからちょっと
Otaku... well, ever since then, a bit—
「水詩頑張れ！」って、もうあの踊っている時の水詩を、「これ頑張れ！」っていう気持ちで
Cheering "Mizushi, do your best!" while dancing, feeling like, "You can do it!"
もうね、でもね、あの視線感じた、見守ってくれてる温かい視線が、なんならちょっとサビ歌ってて
But you know, I felt your gaze watching over me warmly. You could've even sung the chorus a bit!
あ、ほんとに！はい来てくれて、あんな時に、なー！飛び入り参加
Oh really! Yes, coming over to join in like that, wow! Surprise guest appearance!
いや本当に、なんか、いろんな思い出がね
Really, all kinds of memories—
蘇ってきて、凄いなんかすっかり楽しんでいる、みんなも楽しんでますか？
came flooding back, and I'm having so much fun. Is everyone else having fun?
楽しんでるー！
Having fun!
どうですか？なんかね、すごいね、水詩のハートんね、水色のハートとかね、そうそうそう、赤い、AZKiの赤いハートとかもね、いっぱいスタンプとかしてくれて、めちゃくちゃ嬉しい
How is it? There were so many stamps—Mizushi's light blue hearts, AZKi's red hearts—making me so happy.
あとみんなあの床になってました。あ、ほんまに？
And everyone turned into floors. Oh really?
いやでも、まだまだこの後も床になれるタイミングいっぱいあるから
But you know, there are still plenty of opportunities to turn into floors later on!
床をすうしている頂いている
You've been floor-worshipping us—
あの、そう、ばっちり。ばっちり。あの、そう、あのね、床って何？っていうね
Exactly. Spot on. But wait, what does "turning into a floor" mean?
あの、方が多いんですよ。なるほど。水詩はばっちり
A lot of people ask that. I see. Mizushi nailed it!
あら、京都ゲームだと思ってたわ。話が早いですね。はい、ということでこの後も
Oh, I thought it was Kyoto games. That was fast! Well, with that said, moving on to—
じゃ次、AZKi、歌っていきたいと思います
Next, AZKi will sing.
ママのことそれで見てる
I've been watching Mama through that—
見られてる、からもう頑張ろう
Being watched, so I'll do my best.
大好きな歌聴けてるから、見てるよ
I'm listening to my favorite song, so I'm watching you!
頑張ります！見てるからね、頑張ってー！
I'll do my best! I'm watching, so do your best!
はい、ということでここからはAZKiのソロパートに行きたいと思います。この、なんだろうな、エモめの感じなのでこの曲からいきたいと思います。聞いてください。「漫ろ雨」
Alright, so from here on, we'll move on to AZKi's solo part. With this emotional vibe, we'll start with this song. Please listen to "Sozoro Ame".
雨の降る朝 坂道の少し下
On a rainy morning, just down the slope,
傘の無い君眺め続けて ただそれだけ
I kept watching you without an umbrella, just doing that.
一言の声をかける 勇気もない
I don't even have the courage to say a single word.
だから、ねぇ。
So, hey...
傘の隙間から零れ落ちた雨
Raindrops spilling from the gaps in the umbrella,
緩やかな坂道を伝り落ちて
trickling down the gentle slope,
この想いを乗せ君のもとへとだ 伝えてくれたらそれでいいのにな
carrying these feelings to you—if only they could reach you, that would be enough.
雨の匂いが消えないの 消えないの
The scent of rain won't fade away, it won't fade away.
二度とない日を逃したくない それなのにさ これくらいの距離くらいも 踏み出せない だから、ねぇ。
I don't want to let go of this irreplaceable day, yet even this short distance I cannot step across. So, hey...
傘の隙間から零れ落ちた雨
Raindrops spilling from the gaps in the umbrella,
緩やかな坂道を伝り落ちて この想いを乗せ君のもとへとだ 伝えてくれたらそれでいいのにな
trickling down the gentle slope, carrying these feelings to you—if only they could reach you, that would be enough.
鳴り止まない雨すべてを包んで
The ceaseless rain envelops everything,
心臓の音さえも届かないの 願うならば ねぇ 届くはずのない そんなことを思うだけで
so that even the sound of my heartbeat cannot reach. If I could wish, hey, just thinking of the impossible—
雲の隙間から覗き出す太陽
Sunlight peering through the gaps in the clouds,
振り返った君の顔目と目が合う
you turn around and our eyes meet.
差し出す傘もう 遅いと気づいて それなのにさ 苦笑う
Realizing that offering my umbrella is too late, yet even so, I wryly smile.
「君が好きです」
"I love you."
ああ、他人事みたいな夜だ
Ah, it's a night that feels like someone else's business.
ばら撒いた星だけがキラリ澄んでいる
Only the scattered stars are glittering and clear.
そんなに綺麗にはなれないや、それでも今夜、往くための歌
I can't be that beautiful, but still, this is a song to keep going tonight.
ああ、ほんの小さな夜だ
Ah, it's just a tiny night.
寝には早く、夜明けはまだ遠く
Too early for sleep, and dawn is still far away.
憧れるには遠く、挫けるにはまだ早いな
Too far to yearn for, too early to give up...
言葉はいつまでも下手だぜ
Words are always so clumsy.
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs get better.
傷付く度、違う生き物だと知るよ
Every time I get hurt, I learn I'm a different creature.
いつだって闇で迷子
Always a lost child in the darkness.
明けない夜があったなら
If there was a night that never broke,
このまま溶けて消えたいや
I'd want to melt and disappear just like this.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there was a night that never broke,
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
don't need to be a glittering star.
ああ、本日も閉店です
Ah, we're closed for today.
どうにかこうにか一日
Somehow or other, through the day,
ひっそりこっそり良く頑張り
quietly and secretly doing my best,
何かは残せたのでしょうか？
did I leave anything behind?
希望的だ 刹那的だ
Optimistic, ephemeral,
楽観的だ でも
optimistic, but...
きっと美しいよ
surely it's beautiful.
言葉はいつまでも下手だぜ
Words are always clumsy.
ため息だけが上手になるよ
Only my sighs get better.
傷付いて、違う生き物だと知って
Getting hurt and knowing I'm a different creature,
それでも精一杯歌うよ
still, I'll sing with all my might.
泣きたい夜があったなら
If there was a night I wanted to cry,
笑えない夜があったなら
if there was a night I couldn't smile,
溶けて消えてなくなって
melting, disappearing, and vanishing,
もう一度ゼロから始めよう
let's start over from zero once more.
明日のことはわからないや
I don't know about tomorrow,
昨日のことも知らないや
and I don't know about yesterday either.
明けない夜があったって
Even if there was a night that never broke,
私は
I...
煌めく星になれなくて良い
don't need to be a glittering star.
みんなもよかったら一緒に歌ってください！ From A to Z!
If you'd like, please sing along with me! From A to Z!
歌を歌う意味を 生き続けていく意味を
The meaning of singing songs, the meaning of continuing to live
考えても答えなんてないと知っている
I know that even if I think about it, there's no answer.
白も 黒も 世界から消えた
White and black disappeared from the world.
そこに何が残るのだろうか
What is left there, I wonder?
いなくなったら 忘れてしまうか
If I disappear, will I be forgotten?
違う 違う 軌跡がここにあるよ
No, no, our footprints are right here.
たった一人の 君と出会えて
Meeting you, who are one of a kind,
私は今を生きてるの
I am living in the present.
これから起こる すべてのことを
All the things that will happen from now on
一緒に見よう 最初から最後までだよ
let's see them together, from the very beginning to the very end.
歌を歌う意味を 生き続けていく意味を
The meaning of singing songs, the meaning of continuing to live,
一歩一歩 確かめるように 見つけよう
let's find it step by step, as if confirming it.
ときに暗く 冷たい世界で
In a sometimes dark and cold world,
弱く脆く 崩れそうになる
becoming weak, fragile, and on the verge of collapsing.
いなくなったら 忘れてしまうか
If I disappear, will I be forgotten?
違う 違う 君の声が聞こえた
No, no, I heard your voice.
たった一人の 君と出会えて
Meeting you, who are one of a kind,
私は今を生きてるの
I am living in the present.
これから起こる すべてのことを
All the things that will happen from now on
一緒に創ろう 最初から最後までだよ
let's create them together, from the very beginning to the very end.
この世界を 大好きでいたいよ
I want to love this world dearly.
時計の針が 0時を指した
The clock hands pointed to midnight.
気が遠くなるような 時間が過ぎた
Time passed as if my senses were fading.
世界は変わる そこに君はいない
The world changes, and you are not there.
それでも良いと思えたんだよ
Even so, I was able to think it was okay.
ここがスタート
This is where it starts.
キミがいるから 一人じゃないから
Since you're here, I'm not alone.
ずっと 一人だけで 同じことばかり
Always just by myself, doing the exact same things,
何か 寂しくなっちゃうよね
somehow feeling a bit lonely, aren't I?
俯いてばかりで 明日もわからない
Just looking down, not even knowing tomorrow.
こんな 足りないものみたいに
Like this, with things feeling lacking from start to finish,
はじめからおしまいまで きっとちいさなわたし
surely I'm a tiny little me.
“A→Z” “K→i” …世界に響いている
"A→Z" "K→i" ...Resonating through the world,
だから
so that's why...
without U――キミがいないときっと
without U——Whenever you're not here,
私は私でいられないんだ
I couldn't be myself at all.
I need U――私を見て、聞いて！
I need U——Look at me, listen to me!
そうしたらきっと届けられるから
If I do, surely I can reach you.
キミがいるって 一人じゃないって
You're here, you're not alone,
歩きどうしなのは 私だけじゃなくて
walking through it isn't just me alone,
きっと こうしているときでも
surely even when I'm like this,
キミは ずっとずっと 頑張っていたんだね
you were always, always trying your best.
私は全部見ているから
I'm watching it all,
つまらなさからてっぺんまで ちいさな心ぜんぶ
from the boredom to the very top, every little heart.
“Z→A” “i→K” …伝える想いがここに
"Z→A" "i→K" ...The thoughts I want to convey are right here,
それは
so that's...
Beside U――キミのそばにいるよ
Beside U——I'll stay right by your side,
どんなに辛く思ったときでも
even when things feel so tough.
I read U――聞かせて、キミの声！
I read U——Let me hear your voice!
そこに私の声を重ねたら
If I overlap my voice right there,
傍にいる――
I'll be by your side...
もらったものを抱え通し
Holding close everything you gave me,
返し足りないくらいだよ
it's still not enough to return it.
一人じゃない わかってもね
Even knowing I'm not alone,
いつまでこうしていられるの？
how long can I keep being like this?
そんなことわからないよ
I don't know things like that,
わからないから歌うんだよ！
so because I don't know, I'll sing!
キミといるこの瞬間
This moment with you,
大切なものにするために――！
to make it something precious...
そうだ
That's right,
without U――キミがいないときっと
without U——Whenever you weren't here,
私は私でいられなかった
I couldn't be myself at all.
I need U――私を見て、聞いて！
I need U——Look at me, listen to me!
そうしたらきっときっとこれからも……
If I do, surely, surely from now on too...
だから
So that's why,
within U――キミのなかにいるよ
within U——I am inside you,
キミがくれたもののその限りに
within the limits of what you gave me.
I with U――どうか、覚えていて！
I with U——Please, always remember!
私がここに立つときはいつも
Whenever I stand here,
キミがいるから 一人じゃないから
because you're here, because I'm not alone.
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
一緒に立ってくれてありがとうコメントで見えてるよ。
Thank you to everyone in the chat for standing up!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい。
Right.
ということで みんな今日のね
So, everyone, today's...
あずきのこの ライブのタイトル タイトルにもありますけれども
in the live's title, it's mentioned, but...
3Dライブ そして
3D Live and...
ニュー ニューインフォメーション
New, new information.
ということで
So,
ここからは お知らせタイムをしたいと思います！
from here on, I'd like to make an announcement!
イェーイ！
Yay!
はい。
Right.
ということでみなさんお待たせしておりますが
So everyone, thank you for waiting, but...
ここで AZKiライブのお知らせが あります！
here, I have an announcement about AZKi's live!
はい。
Right.
ということで まず 9月12日の
So first, September 12th's...
あずき エイジライブ
AZKi A's Live,
リワインド＆リユニオン
"Rewind & Reunion"...
ですが ええ 初めの 池袋晴れ舞台での開催から
However, um, from the holding at Ikebukuro Harebutai,
配信限定に 切り替わります！
it will switch to stream-only!
めちゃくちゃめちゃくちゃ悔しいですけど
It's super, super regrettable, but...
今回はいろんなことを考えて 色々とめちゃくちゃ話し合った結果
this time, thinking about various things and having lots of discussions,
えっと 現地開催ではなく
um, rather than holding it in-person,
配信限定と なります。
it will be stream-only.
はい この日はですね えっと 2019年の12月29日に止まった 時計をですね もう一度進めたいと 思って
This day is, um, well, trying to advance the clock that stopped on December 29th, 2019 once again,
いた ライブなんですけれども
it was a live where I felt that,
今の状況を考えると 現地での開催は厳しい 難しいという判断を 致しました。
but considering the current situation, I made the judgment that holding it in-person would be difficult and hard.
はい ええとね 本当に めちゃくちゃギリギリまで 悩んだんですけど
Yes. Um, really, I worried about it right until the very last moment,
あずきも あずきチームの みんなもとってもね めちゃくちゃ準備していたし
and AZKi, and everyone on the AZKi team prepared so very much,
本当に とっても楽しみにしていたので もうめちゃくちゃ 悔しい思い出でいっぱい です。
and we were really looking forward to it, so I have a lot of regrettable memories.
はい でも ま いつまでもね 足を止めて後ろを 見ていてもいけないなと 思って いまして
Yes, but, well, I can't just stop my feet and keep looking back forever, I thought and felt that.
なので ええと 同じ 9月12日に 配信ではあるんですけど
So, um, the same September 12th is a streaming one, but...
最終号して 開拓者のみんなと一緒に前に 進みたいと思って います。
I want to move forward together with the pioneer fans for the final show!
ということで 画像 お願いします！
So, um, image please!
AZKi 8th LIVE REWIND & REUNION リリアーズ 2021年 9月12日 スタートが17時 @ZaNにて ストリームオンリーに なります。
AZKi 8th LIVE "REWIND & REUNION", Liliaaz, September 12, 2021. Start is at 17:00 at ZaN (Stream only).
チケットは なんと 今から 購入できます！
Tickets are actually on sale starting right now!
はい あとね ちょっと少し 後になるかもしれないんだけど この日に ええ 新しい挑戦を したくて はい 開拓者のみんなに 手伝って欲しいことが あります。
Right, also um, it might be a bit later, but on this day, um, I want to do a new challenge, and yes, I have something I want to ask the pioneer fans to help with.
心して 心して 心して皆さん 準備を
Please, please, please prepare everyone.
して おいてください。後日 発表いたします。
I'll announce it at a later date.
はい、あづきのを、
Check out...
あの、なんだ？
um, what was it?
固定、固定コメント、
The pinned comment...
固定コメントから、えっと、チケットの、えっと、URLが貼れとって
has the ticket URL pinned in it, so please, please—
ぜひぜひ、ぜひぜひぜひぜひ、こちらからチケット購入していただけるととってもとってもとってもとっても励みになりますので、よろしくお願いいたします！
please buy your tickets from there! It would mean the absolute world to us, so thank you so much!
お願いします！お願いします！
Please! Please!
そして、えー、今回もですね、なんとオープニングアクトの方をお呼びいたしました！
And, um, this time as well, we've invited an opening act!
オープニングアクトはこの方です！画像お願いします！
Our opening act is this person! Please roll the image!
はーちゃんです！いえーい！えい！
HACHI-chan! Yay! Yeah!
えーっと、そのはーちゃんにもね、あの命を歌ってもらったりとか、あづきも光の向こうへを、あの出させていただたりとかしたのですごい本当に
HACHI-chan sang a song with us, and we also got to perform "Hikari no Mukou e," so it really—
この、え、エースライブ、エースライブ、はーちゃんだ！はーちゃんだ！今気づいた
This, uh, AZKi LIVE... AZKi LIVE... It's HACHI! It's HACHI-chan! I just realized!
ということで、はーちゃんが来てくれます！のでちょっとね、もう本当に頑張ろう！なんかこう応援に、あの応援にし来てくれるし
So HACHI-chan is coming! So we're gonna do our best! She's coming to support us, and—
あの現地開催できないけれども、配信でみんな一緒に盛り上がって行きたいなと思っております！はい！
even though we can't hold an in-person venue, we want everyone to get hyped together through the stream! Yes!
そして、新グッズございます！画像お願いします！
And we have brand new merchandise! Please show the image!
あづきのワンマンライブといえば新しいTシャツということで今回も2種類作りましたー！どっちも普段からおしゃれに、おしゃれにね、切れると思うのでぜひぜひ買ってくださーい！こちらも今からあづきオフィシャルストアで購入可能ですー！
Speaking of AZKi's solo live, that means new T-shirts! We made two kinds this time! Both are super stylish for everyday wear, so please be sure to grab them! They are available for purchase right now on the AZKi Official Store!
はーい！ということがで、またねTwitterの方でもお知らせいたしますので
Right! So we'll also announce this on Twitter later, so—
概要欄に書いて…お、概要欄に書いたそうです！いま、いま、はい！
Oh, it's written in the description box... Oh, they already wrote it in the description box! Right now, yeah!
概要欄にいま更新をされたので、こうなんだ？リロードすれば…飛べる！
It was just updated in the description box, so if you reload... you can go there!
そうなので、ぜひぜひ！いやそう、買いたくしゃのみんなにやってもらいたいことにこのね、そうライブTシャツは絶対必須なので、ぜひよろしくお願いいたします！買いたくしゃの皆様様！
So definitely! Well, for everyone who wants to buy it, getting this live T-shirt is an absolute must, so please, I'd really appreciate it, everyone who wants to buy!
はい、ということでライブのお知らせもしたし、いや本当にねみんなと直接集まれないのは本当に寂しいですけれどもでもね
Right, so we've made the live announcements, and honestly, it's so sad that we can't all gather in person, but you know...
みんなそれぞれの場所でなんかこう楽しんでもらえたらいいなって思って、いますので、どうぞ9月12日はよろしくおねがいします！あづきチームも
we hope you'll have fun in your respective places, so please look forward to September 12th! AZKi's team as well...
ね、こうなんかこれまではとはなんか同じことじゃなくて新しいことにも挑戦して前に進んでいくのでこれからもついてきてくれますか？ついてきてください！ということで
You know, we're taking on new challenges instead of doing the same old things and moving forward, so will you keep following us? Please keep following us! So...
はい、お知らせはこのへんにしまして、そろそろね
Yeah, let's leave the announcements at that, and soon...
いやライブも最後、最後、最後ということで最後の曲に、あ、もう最後か！あっというま！最後の曲に行きたいと思いますので水しを呼びたいと思います！それじゃあみんな行くよ！せーの！
The live is reaching the very end, the very end, the very end, meaning the final song—ah, it's already the end? Time flies! We're about to head into our final song, so let's call out Mizu-shi! Alright, everyone, here we go! Ready, set!
みずしー！
Mizu-shi!
わあ！めちゃめちゃよかったよ、嬉しい！
Wow! That was so good, I'm so happy!
久々に側でなんか歌声聞いたけど や、特等席だからね！
It's been a while since I heard you sing up close— Well, it's the front row seat!
いや、ほんとに、や、ほんとに、やっぱみんな生で聞けるのやっぱめちゃめちゃよかった！
Seriously, yeah, really, being able to hear everyone live is just so great!
そう、久々にこう横でさ、 ね、そうだよね。
Yeah, standing side by side like this for the first time in a while... Right, exactly.
聞きだけど、やっぱしみるね、生は。
I wanted to listen, it really hits different live.
しみた！いや嬉しいな、水しにこうやって言われるとなんかちょっとポカポカしてくる。
It hit me! I'm so happy hearing you say that, it makes me feel all warm inside.
ポカポカ？ポカポカ？おばあちゃんパワー
Warm? Warm? Grandma power!
ポカポカ、ポカポカをいただいて。
Receiving all that warmth!
え、しかも、Eins Liveおめでとう！ありがとうございます！
And on top of that, congratulations on the Eins Live! Thank you so much!
すごいじゃん！8回目やってるのかえ！
That's amazing! It's your 8th one, right?
そう、いや本当にでも振り返ると、いやあ、すごいやってきたなってなんか
Yeah, really, looking back, wow, we've really come a long way...
やりすぎぐらいありますけど、
We've done almost too much, if anything!
そんな水しからもお知らせがあるということであります！みなさん心して、お聞きください！おきですか？
And Mizu-shi has an announcement as well! Everyone, prepare yourselves and listen up! Ready?
ということでまずは、画像お願いします！
With that, first, please roll the image!
はい！えー、この度ジェムズカンパニーはサードライブを開催いたしまーす！イエーイ！
Yes! Um, GEMS COMPANY will be holding our 3rd live! Yay!
はい！えー、日付が11月の19日金曜日から21日日曜日の、えー、合計5公演となっておりまーす！
Yes! Um, the dates run from Friday, November 19th to Sunday, November 21st, for a total of 5 performances!
すごい！ね、多いよ！そして、会場は山野ホールさんになりまーす！よよぎ駅から近いらしいよ！
Amazing! Right, that's a lot! And the venue will be Yamano Hall! Apparently it's super close from Yoyogi Station!
ま、チェンジのウェーブということで、変化の波を起こしていきたいと思います！
And since it's called CHANGENOWAVE, we want to create waves of change!
そして、チケットの詳細についてはこちら画像お願いします！
And for details regarding tickets, please check the image here!
はい、ま、リアルチケットと配信チケットがあるんですけれども、まあこういうご時世もありまして、どうしてもちょっと行けないなっていう人は配信チケットを買っていただきましたし、もちろんね、あのリアル行けるよっていう
Yes, so there are both in-person tickets and streaming tickets, and well, given the times, for those who unfortunately can't make it, we'd love for you to buy the streaming tickets, and of course, for those who can come in person...
方は買っていただきたいので ぜひぜひ あの、神聖ジムスカンパニー、急に新たに急にになったジムスカンパニーよ！見に来てください。
If you're able to buy tickets, please come see the newly formed Jimus Company!
そうだ！
That's right!
ここのね、QRコードでね、飛べるので、ぜひぜひよろしくおねがいします！
You can jump right from the QR code here, so please check it out!
お願いします！
Please!
五公演なんて、もうすごすぎますよ！
Five performances is amazing!
で、毎回ね、ジムカンってなんかご公演なの？
And every time, why is Jimukan five performances?
おぉ、すごい！すごい！
Oh, amazing! Amazing!
もう見に来て、絶対見に来たほうがいい！
You've gotta come see it, definitely!
本当に、見に来たほうがいいよ！来てくれ！来てくれ！
Seriously, you should come! Come on!
来てくれ！見に行きたいよ！
Come on! I want to go!
行きたいし、見ます！
I want to go, I'll watch!
はい！ありがとうございます！
Yes! Thank you!
はい、ということで、いやあ、もう最後の曲だって。
Yes, so... wow, it's already the last song.
な、早すぎ！
W-what, too fast!
早すぎ？
Too fast?
秒やねんけど、な、まだまだやりたい！
It feels like seconds, like, I want to do more!
まだもう一周！
Another round!
もう二周くらいできる！
We could do about two more rounds!
もう二周できる！
We can do another round!
水しーとならもう二周はできる！
With Mizu-shii, we could do two more rounds!
いやもう、定期的に呼んで！
Yeah, just invite us regularly!
ええ、嬉しい！え、定期的に？いつでもいくからさ！
Yay, happy! Regular? I can go anytime!
本当！え、嬉しい！
Really? Yay, I'm happy!
私たちさ、今年のさ、4月1日にさ、あずきジムス会社に加入したんですけど、
Back on April 1st this year, we joined AZKi's Jimus Company, right?
そう、一時的に加入してくれたよね。あのエイプリルフールの企画で。そうそうそうそうそうそう！
You temporarily joined us for that April Fools' prank. That's right!
まさかジムスカンパニーに、そう、この、あ、さ、に、この衣装だよね、この、そう、この衣装をね、あずきを着させてもらってさ。
Never expected in Jimus Company... wearing this very outfit, AZKi let me wear this outfit.
そうそうそうそうそうそう、似合ってたよ！
Right, right, right, it looked great on you!
そう、なんで、ちょっとまた、あの衣装を着たいな。
So, why, I'd love to wear that outfit again.
スタッフ、スタッフさん！
Staff, staff-san!
あるかな、一緒。頼んだよ！
Is there one? Together. I asked!
頼んだよ！勝手なことばっかり嫌がってって思われるわ。
I asked! People will think I'm just saying selfish things.
思われちゃう。
They'll think that.
え、でもそういうのもしてみたいね。
Eh, but I'd love to try things like that too.
なんかそういうのお揃いの衣装なんてめちゃくちゃいいじゃないですか。
Matching outfits like that would be so awesome, right?
じゃあ逆に水しーなの、これ、これ来て。
Then conversely, Mizu-shii's, wear this one, this one.
あの、ママのアイドル衣装みんなのさ、実は初めてなの、生で。
Um, seeing everyone's mama idol outfits live for the first time.
そうだ！そうだ！
That's right! That's right!
前まであの、ポワーンってなってたやつ。
Before, it was all poof-poof.
そう、冠名ポワーンってなってるやつしか知らんかったから。
Right, because we only knew the crown-poof version.
そう、そうそう！この姿になってから水しーはじめて。
Right, right! Ever since taking this form, it's Mizu-shii's first time.
そう、かわいい！
So, cute!
かわいい！かわいい！水しー！
Cute! Cute! Mizu-shii!
次の曲ね、そんなかわいい衣装に合うよ。
The next song matches such a cute outfit.
お！おお！やっちゃいますか！
Oh! Ooh! Shall we do it?
いやあ、この曲、いや、めちゃいい曲なんだよな。
Man, this song, it's such a good song.
ずっと聞いててくれる。そう、いい曲なんで。
Keep listening. Yeah, it's such a good song.
今日は心して楽しんでいただきますよ！
Today you're going to enjoy it with all your heart!
はい！はい！
Yes! Yes!
それでは皆さん、最後の曲になります。聞いてください！
Now everyone, it's the final song. Please listen!
せーの！ときめきドリームライン！
Ready, go! Tokimeki Dream Line!
ドリームライン まっすぐ未来へ ここから今へ
Dream Line, straight to the future, from here to now...
今！
Now!
ねえ、それは恋するみたいに
Hey, it's like falling in love,
走り出すハートノオト
a heart note starting to run!
ドキドキが愛しさで
Palpitations turned into affection,
苦しいくらい
almost painful.
そう、夢は恋によく似てる
Yes, dreams are a lot like love,
誰よりも近づきたくて
wanting to get closer than anyone else.
弱気になったりツラくても
Even when feeling weak or having a hard time,
絶対嫌いにならない
I will never hate it.
これしかないと思えるものに出会えたことがもう奇跡の始まりだよ！！
Finding the one thing I can rely on is already the beginning of a miracle!
ドリームライン まっすぐ未来へ続く今日を
Dream Line, continuing straight to the future today...
(思いっきり) どこまでも駆け抜けるよ
Running through anywhere with all my might!
ドリームライン 夢見ることに遠慮しないでトライしたい 行こう！！
Dream Line, don't hold back on dreaming, let's try and go!!
ときめきを信じて
Believe in the excitement!
ねえ 同じ気持ちを重ねて それぞれのハートノオト
Hey, overlapping the same feelings, each other's heart notes,
キラキラと輝くよ
shining brightly.
みんなとなら
If we're with everyone...
最初はひとりて願った 小さくて大きな夢
A small and big dream I first wished for alone,
今は違うね たくさんの 仲間と育てる夢
now it's different, a dream nurtured with many friends.
無謀かもね、と誰かが言ったけれどひとつひとつ今へとつながったよ
Someone said it might be reckless, but one by one they connected to the present.
ドリームライン 大切な点と点を結び
Dream Line, connecting precious dots,
(強くね) どこまでも広がってゆく
expanding everywhere.
ドリームライン いくつもの努力味方にして飛び出そう
Dream Line, making our efforts our ally, let's jump out!
さあときめきを響かせ
Now let the excitement resonate,
憧れが道案内
admiration is our guide.
(こっちだよ) たまに落ち込んじゃう時には
Sometimes when feeling down,
(見見て) 心の奥を
look deep into your heart,
(クラン☆) 突き抜くヒカリ (ライン) 未来向きに伸びてゆく
a piercing light (line) extending toward the future!
(どこまでも) ススメ！！
Go ahead anywhere!
(さあ ススメ！！) ドリームライン まっすぐ未来へ続く今日を
Dream Line, continuing straight to the future today...
(思いっきり) どこまでも駆け抜けるよ
Running through anywhere with all my might!
ドリームライン 夢見ることに遠慮しないでトライしたい 行こう！！
Dream Line, don't hold back on dreaming, let's try and go!!
ときめきを信じて
Believe in the excitement!
ねぇ 同じ気持ちを重ねて それぞれのハートノオト キラキラと輝くよ みんなとなら
Hey, overlapping the same feelings, each other's heart notes, shining brightly with everyone!
最初はひとりで願った 小さくて大きな夢
A small and big dream I first wished for alone,
今は違うね たくさんの仲間と育てる夢
now it's different, a dream nurtured with many friends.
無謀かもねと 誰かが言ったけれど
Someone said it might be reckless,
ひとつひとつ今へ つながったよ！
but one by one they connected to the present!
あ
Ah
ドリームライ...
Dream line...
大切な点と点を結び
Connecting important dots together,
どこまでも広がり続けてゆけ
keeping it spreading endlessly.
ドリームライ...
Dream line...
いくつかの努力を味方にして
Turning your hard work into your ally,
飛び出そう さあ
let's leap out, now!
ときめきを響かせ
Make your heartbeat echo.
あそこが道案内
That place is guiding the way.
たまに落ち込んじゃう
Sometimes when you feel down,
時には見て 心の奥を
look deep inside your heart.
突き抜ける光 未来向きに伸びてゆく
A piercing light reaches toward the future.
どこまでも進め 進め
Keep advancing, no matter how far!
ドリームライ まっすぐ未来へ
Dream line... Straight into the future,
続く今日を
through this ongoing today.
どこまでも駆け抜けられるよ
You can run through it anywhere.
ドリームライ 夢みることに遠慮しないで
Dream line... Don't hold back on dreaming.
旅したい 旅行
I want to travel...
ときめきを信じて
Believe in the excitement.
ときめきドリームライ
Exciting dream line...
ありがとうございました！
Thank you very much!
楽しかったー！
That was so fun!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
えい、ちびアズライブ見てくれてった！
Hey, thanks for watching Chibi AZKi's live!
見取ったよ、見取ったよ！
I saw it, I saw it!
よかった、めっちゃよかった！
It was great, so great!
なんか関西弁になってるけどさ、移ったんかな？
You sound kind of Kansai-ben, did it rub off on you?
ありがとうな、めちゃめちゃ嬉しい！
Thank you so much, I'm so happy!
一緒に帰って、ちびアズ
Let's go home together, Chibi AZKi.
お持ち帰りされていきます
Being taken home.
お持ち帰りまーす！家路を急げー！
Taking you home! Hurry home!
今日から水信のちびアズになりますやったー！
Starting today, I'm MizuShin's Chibi AZKi! Yay!
デスクに置いてやろう、置いて、置いて貰いまーす
I'll put you on my desk, get you placed.
一緒に寝ような！やった！えづけするで！
Let's sleep together! Yay! I'll feed you!
アンコで、アンコ食べよう、おパーティだ！
With anko, let's eat anko, it's a party!
ではそろそろちびアズは、ねぶたーので、締めたいと思います
Well, it's about time for Chibi AZKi to wrap it up.
ピンポンパンポン
Ping pong pan pong...
本日はAZKiの魔法放送をご覧いただき誠にありがとうございました！
Thank you very much for watching AZKi's Magical Broadcasting today!
ぜひ感想をAZKiの魔法放送で呟いてくださいね！
Please tweet your impressions on AZKi's Magical Broadcasting!
一つ一つ読んでいきますよ、ドーン！
I'll read them one by one, boom!
そして、この後は水信も一緒にめんげアフタートークがあるらしいですよ、皆さんよろしく！よろしゅう！
And after this, there's an after-talk with MizuShin as well, everyone please look forward to it!
それでは、バイバーイ！
Well then, bye-bye!
AZKi 8th LIVE REWIND & REUNION